A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Office of the Secretary of Education, 1994; 1998-2006
Library of Virginia
- VII. Additional Records (accession 44681), 1994; 1998; 2000-2006., Extent: 9.64 cubic feet (29 boxes). (Box 137-165)
  - Subseries VII.A. Correspondence and Supporting Documentation, Office of the Secretary, 2001-2006., Extent: 5.95 cubic feet. (Box 137-153)
    - Secretary of Public Safety, 2002-2003; 2005. (Box 148, Folder 5)
    - Secretary of Technology, 2002-2005. (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - Secretary of Transportation, 2004. (Box 149, Folder 4)
    - Secure Virginia Panel, 2002-2003. (Box 151, Folder 5)
    - Southern Virginia Univeristy, 2002. (Box 141, Folder 3)
    - SREB (Southern Regional Education Board), 2003-2005. (Box 141, Folder 4)
    - Special Education, 2002. (Box 145, Folder 6)
    - States Institute on International Education in the Schools, 2003. (Box 141, Folder 5)
    - Renovation of the Old State Library, 7 February 2005. (Box 137, Folder 3)
    - Superintendent of the Year, 2002. (Box 145, Folder 7)
    - Tobacco, 2002-2003. (Box 141, Folder 6)
    - United States Senate, 2002-2003. (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - VACIE (Virginia Council for International Education), 2002-2003. (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - VASSP, 2004. (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Venture Philanthropy Partners, 2005. (Box 149, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Administrative Dispute Act, 2002. (Box 144, Folder 6)
    - Virginia A.L. Philpott Manufacturing Extension Partnership, 2004. (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Asian Advisory Board, 2003-2004. (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Association of School Superintendents, 2003-2004. (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Automobile Dealers Association, 2002; undated. (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Business-Education Partnership, 2002-2004. (Box 149, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Career Education Foundation (VCEF), 2002; 2004-2005. (Box 144, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Career Education Foundation (VCEF), 2002-2003. (Box 144, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Citizen-Soldier Support Council, 2004. (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Coalition of Latino Organizations, 2002. (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Corps, 2003. (Box 151, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Economic Bridge, 2002-2005. (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Economic Bridge, 2003. (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Economic Developers Association, 2002; 2004. (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Freedom of Information Advisory Council, 2004. (Box 149, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Foundation for the Humanities, 2003. (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Head Start, 2002. (Box 145, Folder 3)
    - Virginia High School League, 2002; 2004. (Box 145, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Historical Society, 2003. (Box 149, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Information Technologies Agency (VITA), 2004-2005. (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Information Technologies Agency (VITA), 2003-2004. (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Institute of Forensic Science and Medicine, 2002. (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Interagency Coordinating Council, 2004. (Box 151, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Israel Advisory Board, 2001-2002. (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Liaison Office, 2002-2003. (Box 144, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Library Association, 2003. (Box 139, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Literacy Foundation, 2002-2004. (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Living Museum, 2002. (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Performing Arts Foundation, 2002; 2004. (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Research and Technology Advisory Commission, 2002-2006. (Box 143, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Satellite Education Network (VSEN), 2002. (Box 143, Folder 7)
    - Virginia School Board Association, 2002-2005. (Box 149, Folder 6)
    - Virginia School Efficiency Review Pilot Program, 2003-2005. (Box 139, Folder 5)
    - Virginia School-To-Work Initiative, 2004. (Box 143, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Space Grant Consortium, 2003. (Box 144, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Student/Parent Mock Election (VSPME), 2005. (Box 144, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Task Force on Campus Sexual Assualt, 2002. (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Tobacco Indemnification and Community Revitalization Commission, 2004. (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Tourism Corporation, 2002. (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Virginia21, 2003-2005. (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Workforce Investment Act, undated. (Box 149, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Workforce Council, 2005. (Box 150, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Workforce Council, 2004. (Box 150, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Workforce Council, 2003. (Box 150, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Workforce Council, 2002. (Box 150, Folder 4)
    - WeatherBug, 2004. (Box 152, Folder 1)
    - WHRO Broadcasting, 2003. (Box 145, Folder 5)
    - Wolf Trap Foundation for the Performing Arts, 2003. (Box 139, Folder 6)
    - Wytheville Training School Culture Center, 2003. (Box 145, Folder 6)
  - Subseries VII.B. Special Projects and Studies, 1994; 1998; 2000-2005., Extent: 2.63 cubic feet. (Box 154-161)
    This subseries is housed in 8 boxes. The processing archivist retained the original order of the files, but arranged them in alphabetical order in thle finding aid to facilitate better access. Boxes 159 and 160 contain the files of Deputy Secretary of Education Sarah Finley. This subseries contains subject files. Researchers should check Series II. Assigned State Agencies, Series IV. Office of the Secretary, and Series VI. Special Projects for additional records.
    - 123 Club, 6 August 2004. (Box 154, Folder 1)
    - Accord Between the Commonwealth of Virginia and the United States Department of Education, Office for Civil Rights, First Bi-Annual Report, 31 January 2002. (Box 158, Folder 1)
    - ACT
      - Memorandum, 2002-2003. (Box 154, Folder 7)
      - Board of Directors Meeting, 24-26 January 2003. (Box 154, Folder 8)
      - Board of Directors Strategic Planning Meeting, 25 April 2003. (Box 155, Folder 1)
      - Board of Directors Meeting, 26-27 April 2003. (Box 155, Folder 2)
      - ACT Assessment 2003 Results - Virginia, August 2003. (Box 155, Folder 3)
      - ACT Assessment 2003 Results - National, August 2003. (Box 155, Folder 3)
      - Annual Meeting, 15-16 October 2003 (part 1). (Box 155, Folder 4)
      - Annual Meeting, 15-16 October 2003 (part 2). (Box 155, Folder 5)
      - Board of Directors Meeting, 23-25 April 2004. (Box 156, Folder 1)
      - Board of Directors Meeting, 23-25 April 2004. (Box 156, Folder 2)
      - Memorandum, 2004. (Box 156, Folder 3)
      - Board of Directors Meeting, 23-25 July 2004. (Box 156, Folder 4)
      - Board of Directors Meeting, 23-25 July 2004. (Box 156, Folder 5)
      - Board of Directors Meeting, 23-25 July 2004. (Box 156, Folder 6)
      - Memorandum, 2004. (Box 156, Folder 7)
      - Annual Meeting, 20-21 October 2004. (Box 157, Folder 1)
      - Annual Meeting, 20-21 October 2004. (Box 157, Folder 2)
      - Annual Meeting, 20-21 October 2004. (Box 157, Folder 3)
      - Memorandums, 2004. (Box 157, Folder 4)
    - Advising Process Project (Legislative Review Process), 2004. (Box 154, Folder 6)
    - Board of Education, Curriculum Framework, Virginia and United States Government, 2001. (Box 161, Folder 4)
    - Board of Education, Curriculum Framework, Civics and Economics, 2001. (Box 161, Folder 4)
    - By Kids For Kids, 2005. (Box 154, Folder 4)
    - Governor's Fellows Program, 2004. (Box 154, Folder 5)
    - I Can Learn Education Systems, 2004-2005. (Box 154, Folder 2)
    - J.E.B Stuart Educational Foundation, 2005. (Box 154, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 2003. (Box 160, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1998; 2000-2001. (Box 161, Folder 5)
    - National Air and Space Museum Education Advisory Committee, 2004. (Box 154, Folder 5)
    - P-16 Education Council Meeting, 22 November 2005. (Box 160, Folder 7)
    - Report on Student Achievement in PASS and Turnaround Specialist Schools, 28 September 2005. (Box 160, Folder 5)
    - Salem City Schools Evaluation Handbook for Administrative Personnel, 13 May 2003. (Box 160, Folder 7)
    - Standards of Learning (SOL)
      - Technical Advisory Committee (TAC), 2002; 2004. (Box 160, Folder 1)
      - High Stakes Testing, 2002. (Box 160, Folder 1)
      - SOL Reform-General, 2002. (Box 160, Folder 1)
      - Consequential Validity Study, 2001. (Box 160, Folder 1)
      - Parents Across Virginia United to Reform SOLs, 2002. (Box 160, Folder 1)
      - Issue Brief ED 5.0: Standards of Learning, 2001. (Box 160, Folder 1)
      - Commission on Education Accountability, 2002. (Box 160, Folder 2)
      - State Board of Education, Accountability Advisory Group, 2001. (Box 160, Folder 3)
    - Standards of Quality (SOQ), 2000-2001. (Box 160, Folder 8)
    - Standards of Quality (SOQ), 2000-2001. (Box 161, Folder 1)
    - A Review of Standards of Quality by Richard L. Boyer, 8 November 1994. (Box 161, Folder 2)
    - The Virginia Standards of Quality, Board of Education, Annual Planning Session, 21-22 June 2001. (Box 161, Folder 3)
    - Stennis Center for Public Service, 2003. (Box 157, Folder 5)
    - Task Force International Education, 29 November 2005. (Box 160, Folder 6)
    - Thurgood Marshall Scholarship Fund, 2005. (Box 154, Folder 5)
    - Tower Club Advisory Board of Governors, 2004. (Box 154, Folder 1)
    - University Faculty Early Retirement Incentive Plans, 2002. (Box 157, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Board of Education Committee on Low Performing School Systems
      - Committee Meeting, 6 January 2004. (Box 159, Folder 1)
      - JLARC Study: Review of Factors and Practices Associated with School Performance in Virginia, 24 November 2003. (Box 159, Folder 1)
      - NGA, Reaching New Heights: Turning Around Low-Performing Schools, undated. (Box 159, Folder 2)
      - Urban School Reform, April 2003. (Box 159, Folder 2)
      - Newsome Park Elementary School, Newport News, High Performing School, October 2002. (Box 159, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous Books, 2000; 2002-2003. (Box 159, Folder 3)
      - Committee Meeting, 21 October 2003. (Box 159, Folder 4)
      - Committee Meeting, 18 November 2003. (Box 159, Folder 5)
      - United States Department of Education, Partnership to Leave No Child Behind Resource Notebook, 29 January 2002. (Box 159, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Career Education Foundation, 2005. (Box 160, Folder 4)
    - Voyager Learning, 2005. (Box 154, Folder 3)
    - Wilder Commission, 2002. (Box 157, Folder 6)
  - Subseries VII.C. Legislative Files, 2002-2004., Extent: 0.88 cubic feet. (Box 162-164)
    The Legislative Files sub-series is housed in 3 boxes and is arranged chronologically by legislative session. This subseries documents the Office of the Secretary of Education's review of education related legislation introduced by members of the Virginia General Assembly between 2002 and 2004. Each file usually contains the text of each bill and Legislative Action Summaries. Additional information on legislation is located in the Records of the Policy Office of Governor Mark R. Warner, Series III. Legislative Files (accession 42414).
    - 2002 Legislative Session
      - Miscellaneous Records (Box 162, Folder 1)
      - HB 11-HB 498 (Box 162, Folder 2)
      - HB 605-HB 886 (Box 162, Folder 3)
      - HB 1022-HB 1370 (Box 162, Folder 4)
      - SB 35-SB 681 (Box 162, Folder 5)
    - 2003 Legislative Session
      - Miscellaneous Records (Box 162, Folder 6)
      - HB 1376-HB 1575 (Box 162, Folder 7)
      - HB 1609-HB 1971 (Box 162, Folder 8)
      - HB 2013-HB 2450 (Box 163, Folder 1)
      - HB 2471-HB 2837 (Box 163, Folder 2)
      - HJR 545-HJR 752 (Box 163, Folder 3)
      - SB 659-SB 987 (Box 163, Folder 4)
      - SB 1025-SB 1327; SJR 305-SJR 425 (Box 163, Folder 5)
    - 2004 Legislative Session
      - House Appropriaions Committee, Amendments to House Bill 30 (Box 163, Folder 6)
      - HB 6-HB 989 (Box 163, Folder 7)
      - HB 318-HB 1296 (Box 164, Folder 1)
      - HB 1313-HB 1445 (Box 164, Folder 2)
      - SB 2-SB 653; SB 969 (Box 164, Folder 3)
  - Subseries VII.D. Weekly Reports, 2002-2005., Extent: 0.18 cubic feet. (Box 165)
    The Weekly Reports subseries is housed in one box, arranged chronologically and contains the weekly reports submitted to the Governor and Chief of Staff by the Secretary of Education. Reports were submitted each Thursday and placed in a binder for the Governor that he took with him at the end of the day on Friday. A second copy of the report was made for the Chief of Staff. Each report contains information on legislation, Governor's initiatives/special projects, agency matters/operations, events/agency visits, audits/investigations/compliance, stakeholder issues and pending decisions. This sub-series provides a weekly account of the issues and policy decisions of the Secretary of Education during the Warner administration.
    - 14 March 2002 to 11 December 2003 (Box 165, Folder 1)
    - 18 December 2003 to 10 February 2005 (Box 165, Folder 2)
    - 17 February 2005 to 13 October 2005 (Box 165, Folder 3)